Guide to the Galerie Jacques Benador Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Galerie Jacques Benador archive
1932-2015
GEN MSS 1427
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
9.83
(15 boxes)
The Galerie Jacques Benador Archive, which spans 1932-2015, contains writings, correspondence, exhibition catalogs, printed material, artworks, and other papers related to Jacques Benador, the D. Benador Gallery, and the Jacques Benador Gallery. Jacques Benador's personal papers—which include a large number of photographs--make up the bulk of the collection, documenting Benador's personal and professional relationships with artists and critics of the postwar European avant-garde, as well as events at both galleries he oversaw. Items of note in the collection include multiple manuscript versions of Lucio Fontana's first Spatialist Manifesto, signed first editions of Fontana's Manifesto Bianco in Italian and Spanish, original artwork by Pierre Alechinsky, Hans Bellmer, Max Ernst, Pierre Tal-Coat, Bram van de Velde, Wols, and others.
Galerie Jacques Benador
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 13 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 14 (long-playing records): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Emmanuel Benador, 2016.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Catalogs and Invitations, 1948-2015. II. Artist Monographs and Publications, 1946-2006. III. Personal Papers and Business Records, 1932-2014. IV. Musical Recordings, 1980-1993. V. Artwork, 1952-1972.
Jacques Benador Gallery
In 1928, Galerie D. Benador was founded in Geneva, Switzerland by David Benador (1893-1974) and his brother Charles (1896-1943). The gallery specialized in works in by old masters, Impressionists, 19th century Barbizon and Swiss school. In 1943, David's son, Jacques Benador (1923-2010), assumed leadership of the gallery and introduced Modern and Contemporary art to the gallery's repertoire. Jacques Benador cultivated relationships with contemporary artists—particularly ones involved with surrealism and abstract art. Jacques, who had a special interest in illustrated books both as a noted publisher and as a collector, also oversaw the production of exhibition catalogs (which were designed to be held in one's hand) that often included a specially prepared text, written by well-known authors; some catalogs also included an original print (or a poster) designed by artists for the first fifty copies of the publishing run. In 1973, Jacques opened his own gallery located in the old city of Geneva under the name "Galerie Jacques Benador". After the passing of David Benador, Jacques Benador—along with his wife, Stella--supervised and directed Galerie D. Benador for several years. Galerie Jacques Benador closed its doors in 2010.
Scope and Contents
The Galerie Jacques Benador Archive, which spans 1932-2015, contains writings, correspondence, exhibition catalogs, printed material, artworks, and other papers related to Jacques Benador, the D. Benador Gallery, and the Jacques Benador Gallery. Jacques Benador's personal papers—which include a large number of photographs--make up the bulk of the collection, documenting Benador's personal and professional relationships with artists and critics of the postwar European avant-garde, as well as events at both galleries he oversaw. Items of note in the collection include multiple manuscript versions of Lucio Fontana's first Spatialist Manifesto, signed first editions of Fontana's Manifesto Bianco in Italian and Spanish, original artwork by Pierre Alechinsky, Hans Bellmer, Max Ernst, Pierre Tal-Coat, Bram van de Velde, Wols, and others.
Art -- 20th Century; Art -- Catalogs; Art -- Collectors and collecting -- Switzerland; Art dealers -- Switzerland; Art -- Exhibitions; Art galleries, Commercial -- Switzerland; Art, Modern; Art museums -- Europe; Modernism (Art) -- Europe; Modernism (Art) -- Europe -- Exhibitions; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Photographs; Art dealers -- 20th Century -- Switzerland; Alechinsky, Pierre, 1927-; Bellmer, Hans, 1902-1975; Char, René, 1907-1988; Ernst, Max, 1891-1976; Fontana, Lucio, 1899-1968; Galerie Jacques Benador; Hartung, Hans, 1904-1989; Tal-Coat, Pierre, 1905-1985; Twombly, Cy, 1928-2011; Velde, Bram van, 1895-1981
- Catalogs and invitations, 1948-2015, undated; Series I; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Contains invitations, catalogs, and printed material related to artist exhibitions at venues including the Jacques Benador Gallery. Similar materials can also be found in Series III, Personal Papers and Business Records.
  Arrangement
  Material within this series maintains the original organization found at time of acquisition.
  - Georges Rouault: Exposition, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Modigliani: Dessins, Gouaches, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Gen Paul, Le Temoin, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Arts Primitifs--Peinture Moderne, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Galerie D. Benador: Dessins et Aquarelles de L'Ecole De Paris, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Aspects de L'Ecole de Paris, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Esteve, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Jean Bazaine: Aquarelles Dessins, Numerote 220, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Nicolas de Stael: Peintures, dessins, collages, aquarelles, tapisseries, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Le Vernissage de L'exposition des Deuvres de Nicolas de Stael, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Paul Klee: Aquarelles et Dessins, Numerote 324, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Lanskoy: Peintures et Gouaches, Numerote 174, circa 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bellmer!, Geneve, Galerie D. Benador Numerote 133, circa 1960s (Box 1)
  - Aleschinsky, Numerote 22 et signe, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Esteve, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Jorn: Peintures, modications, gouches, ceramiques 1946-1961 (Box 1)
  - Riopelle, Numerote 58, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Calendrier des Expositions, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Sam Francis: Oeuvres de 1951-1960, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Louis Soutter: 1981-1942, Numerote 21, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Tradition des Arts Primatifs: Afrique, Oceanie, Amerique, Numerote 17, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Cy Twombly: Peintures, Dessins, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Artistes Americans, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Frank Lobdell: Peintures, Gouches, Dessins, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Le Monde Frotte a la Mine de Plomb par Max Ernst, ex. de Jacques Benador, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Maryan: Peintures, dessins, gravures, oeuvres de 1955-1965, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Charchoune: Oeuvres de 1927-1967 (Box 1)
  - Man Ray: Sculptures Dada, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Chirico, Ernst, Tanguy: Dessins, frottages, collages, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Lucio Fontana: Dessins, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Bram Van Velde: Lavis, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Pierre Klossowski: Crayons de Couleurs 1972, Numerote 91, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Joan Miro: Huiles, Gouches, Aquarelles, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Salvatore Scarpitta: Oeuvres de 1958 a 1964, Numerote 19, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Alberto Burri: Oeuvres Recentes, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Kurt Seligmann: Peintures, Dessins, Gravures, Livres, Numerote 10, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Martial Raysse: Sic Transit Gloria Mundi, 1974-1974 (Box 1)
  - Cardenas, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Rebecca Horn, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Christo: Trois Projets Pour Geneve, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Fontana: Dessins, Gravures, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Christian Dotrement: Logogrammes, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Vernissage--Richard Muller: Dessins et Gravures, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Kurt Schwitters: Collages, Peintures, Objets, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Henri Matisse: Dessins, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Tal-Coat: Oeuvres de 1925 a 1947, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Lucio Fontana: Peintures, Dessins, Gravures Rares Multiples, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Alberto Giacometti: Gravures Rares Dessins, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Hans Hartung: Peintures, Pastels, Gravures, Oeuvres de 1935 a 1987, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Henri Michaux: Peintures, Dessins, Estampes, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Matta: Pastels Geants, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Catalogue Giacometti: Collection Lust, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Max Ernst: Explorateur-Createur, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Parcours D'une Galerie, 1928-2003 (75 Ans.) (Box 2)
  - Tal-Coat: Aquarelles Inedites, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Christie's Catalog: 27 April 2015 with notes (Box 2)
  - Picasso Portraits, 2015 (Box 2)
  - Copy of "Louis Soutter" by Herman Hesse, undated (Box 2)
- Artist monographs and publications, 1946-2006; Series II; 2.08; (2 boxes)
  Contains artist monographs and publications, including several documenting the work of artists represented by the Jacques Benador Gallery.
  - Deux Traces Vertes--Du Boucher and Tal-Coat, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Existential Portraits--George Condo, 2006 (Box 4 (Oversize))
  - Cahier d'ombres --Philippe Denis and Joan Miro, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Lucio Fontana: handwritten documents, original manuscripts, and manifestos, 1946-1948 (Box 3)
  - La Noce Noire--Andre Frenaud and Jean Bazaine, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Picasso sur la place--Helene Parmelin, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Picasso Paints a Portrait--David Douglas Duncan, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Picasso--Printmaker: A Perpetual Metamorphosis, 2008 (Box 4 (Oversize))
  - La folle du jour--Bram van Velde and Maurice Blanchot, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Tal-Coat--Jean Leymarie, 1992 (Box 4 (Oversize))
- Personal papers and business records, 1932-2014; Series III; 3.17; (8 boxes)
  Material within this series have been organized into seven subseries: File I-III, File IV, File V, File VI, File VII, File VIII, Uncollected Notes. This arrangement reflects the original order of materials at time of acquisition, including the maintenance of Jacques Benador's filing system for his personal papers, which involved keeping items in bound volumes of annotated plastic page covers. For preservation purposes, a majority of items were removed from these page covers and photocopies were made to retain a record of Mr. Benador's annotations. These preservation photocopies are included in folders with the original materials.
  Contains materials related to Jacques Benador, the Jacques Benador Gallery, and events, publications, and ephemera related to the Gallery. Materials include correspondence, notes, photographs, documentation of exhibitions, and various personal and professional ephemera.
  - Files I-III, 1954-2014
    Materials contain originals and photocopies of photographs, correspondence between Jacques Benador and artists, and pieces of ephemera and printed material related to the Jacques Benador Gallery.
    - File I--annotated photocopies of images and personal papers, undated (Box 5)
    - File II--annotated images and personal papers, 2010-2014, undated (Box 5)
    - File III--correspondence, 1954-1976 (Box 5)
    - File III--correspondence, 1954-1976 (Box 5)
    - File III--correspondence, 1954-1976 (Box 5)
    - File III--photographs of Jean Messagier exhibition, 1974 (Box 5)
  - File IV
    - Photograph of Chez Messagier, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of S.H.S.G. de Lichtenstein, Exper. G. Liebmann, and Mme. Lillaz, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of les freres Loeb; CJean, Messagier, Poliakoff and Macelle Poliakoff, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of les freres Loeb and Poliakoff, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Pierre and Edouard Loeb, Stella Benador, Poliakoff, Messagier, undated (Box 6)
    - Unidentified photographs, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of A, Schoeller, and Jacques Benador, undated (Box 6)
    - Unidentified photographs, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Andre Schoeller, Jr. and Messagier, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Messagier, Bram van Velde, Jacques and Stella Benador, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Jacques and Stella Benador, P. Sarto, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Messagier, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Edmond Quinche, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Max Ernst at Chez Saddrudin, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Saddrudin, Max Ernst, Jacques Benador, Edwin Engelberts, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Saddrudin, Jacques Benador, Max Ernst, and Edwin Engelberts, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Max Ernst at Chez Saddrudin Aga Khan (Geneve), undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Tal-Coat and Jacques Benador, Saint Prex, circa 1972 (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Tal-Coat, P. Sarto, circa 1972 (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Tal-Coat, P. Sarto, circa 1972 (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Tal-Coat, Jacques Benador, Christian du Manoir, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Tal-Coat and his work, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Modigliani with inscription from Paulette Jourdain, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Fernand Leger, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Paul Klee, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Jacques Benador and unidentified person, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Jacques Benador, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Pierre Aleschinsky, Bram van Velde, Jacques Putman, Jacques Benador, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Antonio Saura, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Jacques Benador with Citroen, circa 1950 (Box 6)
    - Texts of Louis Soutter on Hermann Hesse and Le Corbusier, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Hans Hartung; Jacques Benador (FIAC), undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Hans Hartung with Jacques Benador (FIAC), 1987 (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Jacques Benador and Henri Maldiney, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Chicago Art Fair and Gustave Dore exhibition, 1980-1984 (Box 6)
    - FIAC 1989 photographs (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Jacques Benador and Salvatore Scarpitta, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Jacques Benador, Bram van Velde, and others, undated (Box 6)
    - Tal-Coat exhibition installation images, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of David Benador, undated (Box 6)
    - Gallery photos, circa 2008 (Box 6)
    - Photocopied correspondence, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Jacques Benador, Mitterand, and others, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Stella Benador and others, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Jean-Louis Prat and others, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Jacques Benador and Henri Maldiney, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Jacques Benador, Claude Hermann, and others, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Jacques Benador and Jean-Paul Croiser, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Marc Chagall, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Pablo Picasso, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Olga Khoklova Picasso, Pablo Picasso, and Jean Cocteau, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Pierre Tal-Coat and others, undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of Salvatore Scarpitta, undated (Box 6)
    - Letter from Sam Francis, 1962 (Box 6)
    - Letter from Andre Frenaud, 1959 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence from Pierre Aleschinsky, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
    - Notes by Pierre Klossowski, undated (Box 6)
    - Correspondence from Avigdor Arikha, circa 1961 (Box 6)
    - Photographs and envelope from Paulette Jourdain, circa 1952 (Box 6)
    - Correspondences from Yvan Taillendier, 1959 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence from Pierre Klossowski, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Letter from Max Ernst, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Postcard from Hans Hartung, circa 1964 (Box 6)
    - Letters from Tal-Coat, circa 1970-1974, undated (Box 6)
    - Joke written by Tal-Coat, circa 1980 (Box 6)
    - Letter from Bram van Velde, undated (Box 6)
    - Correspondence from and related to Jean Fautrier, undated (Box 6)
    - Correspondence from Esteve, 1963-1964 (Box 6)
    - Letters from Maryan and Annette Maryan, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Letter to Claude Givaudan, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Letter from Balthus, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Letter and photos from Lionel Prejger, 1977 (Box 7)
    - Shigeru Onishi catalog, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Andre Barelier: "8 Sculptures 1973-1975" catalog, undated (Box 7)
    - Photographs of Dalton Baldwin, Jacques Benador, circa 1984 (Box 7)
    - Transcript of book chapter from "Une arriere boutique secrete", 2009 (Box 7)
    - Debut: Metamorphoses, undated (Box 7)
    - Benador Gallery calendar of exhibitions, 1962 (Box 7)
    - Genvieve Asse print, undated (Box 7)
    - Photograph of Pierre Charbonnier, undated (Box 7)
    - Photograph of Benador Gallery facade, undated (Box 7)
    - Letter from Serge Charchoune, undated (Box 7)
    - Program for Tal-Coat event, 2011 (Box 7)
    - Photograph of Jacques Benador, undated (Box 7)
    - Pierre Nahon, Marianne, Marchands, un portrait, undated (Box 7)
    - Jacques Benador portrait printout, undated (Box 7)
    - Photograph of Jacques and Stella Benador, undated (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 7)
    - Gerard Souzay concert program, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Photograph of Pascal Honegger and Jacques Benador, undated (Box 7)
  - File V, 1946-2004
    - Terre des hommes sign, undated (Box 8)
    - Benador gallery booklet and photographs, circa 2003 (Box 8)
    - Conversations avec Horst Janssen, circa 1988 (Box 8)
    - Letter from Esteve, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Letter from Frank Lobdell, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Jean Dubuffet information sheet, circa 1985 (Box 8)
    - Yaacov Agam drawings, 1962 (Box 8)
    - Charles Lapique notecard and matchbook, circa 1980 (Box 8)
    - Jean Messagier notecards, 1973-1977 (Box 8)
    - Hugues Cuenod concert program, 1982 (Box 8)
    - Newspaper clipping, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Photograph of Benador Gallery exterior, circa 2004 (Box 8)
    - Tal-Coat catalog mock-up, undated (Box 8)
    - Letter from Serge Charchoune, 1967 (Box 8)
    - Letter from Rene Char, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Letter to Nusch Eluard, circa 1946 (Box 8)
    - Invitation to Tal-Coat reception, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Letter from Jean Clair, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Paul Klee biography notes by his son Felix Klee, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Nicolas de Stael biography notes by Jean Leymarie, undated (Box 8)
    - Letter from Edwin Engelberts, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Letter from Marcel Arland, undated (Box 8)
    - Bram van Velde biography notes by Jean Leymarie, undated (Box 8)
    - Postcard from Sadruddin Aga Khan, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Autographed Marc Chagall catalog, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Letter from Pierre Klossowski, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence from Paulette Jourdain, 1951-1953 (Box 8)
    - Bellmer!, 1966 (Box 8)
      This limited edition catalog was designed specifically for the Galerie D. Benador, contains an original photograph by Hans Bellmer, and was the personal copy of Jacques Benador.
  - File VI, 1932-1976, undated
    - Photographs of Jacques Benador, undated (Box 9)
    - Letter from James Lord, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Letter from Edwin Engelberts, 1990 (Box 9)
    - David Benador Gallery ledger, 1932-1944 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence and papers, 1943-1971 (Box 9)
    - Letter from Pierre Charbonnier, 1965 (Box 9)
    - Artwork price list, undated (Box 9)
    - Letter from Marie-Madeleine Opalka, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Letter from Andre Frenaud, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Letter from Avigdor Arikha, 1963 (Box 9)
    - Letter from Jean Messagier, undated (Box 9)
    - Letter from Pierre Lecuire, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Photograph of Timothy Baum and Jacques Benador, circa 1987 (Box 9)
    - Photocopied images of Benador portrait and George Condo drawing, 2010, undated (Box 9)
    - Inventory list from Oskar Schloss Librairie du Chateau D'Art, 1946 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1990 (Box 9)
    - Pierre Tal-Coat notes, undated (Box 9)
    - Meeting notes--Diego Giacometti, undated (Box 9)
    - Notes from Pietro Sarto conference, undated (Box 9)
    - Photograph of Georges Braque, undated (Box 9)
    - Horst Janssen: drawing, photographs, correspondence, circa 1988 (Box 9)
    - Venice 73 poster, 1973 (Box 9)
    - Louis Soutter catalog maquette, undated (Box 9)
    - Cy Twombly catalog maquette, undated (Box 9)
    - Max Ernst catalog maquette, undated (Box 9)
    - Invitation for Paul Klee exhibition, circa 1959 (Box 9)
    - Manifesto Blanco, circa 1946 (Box 9)
    - Programs, 1946-1983 (Box 9)
    - Notes on Bram van Velde, undated (Box 9)
    - Letter and pamphlet from Pierre Lecuire, 1995 (Box 9)
    - Orson Welles project notes, undated (Box 9)
    - Nicolas de Stael catalog and maquette, undated (Box 9)
    - "Tradition des Arts Primitifs" catalog maquette, undated (Box 9)
    - Tal-Coat catalog maquette, undated (Box 9)
    - Letter from Ninon Hesse, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Notes on artists, undated (Box 9)
  - File VII, 1962-2013
    - Condolence card for Hans Hartung, circa 1989 (Box 10)
    - Tal-Coat etchings and note, undated (Box 10)
    - Photograph of Henri Presset, 2013 (Box 10)
    - Wifredo Lam statement, circa 1962 (Box 10)
    - Unidentified artwork, undated (Box 10)
    - Letter from Lionello Venturi, 1962 (Box 10)
    - Salvatore Scarpitta drawing, circa 1973 (Box 10)
    - Invitation to Esteve exhibition, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Michel Butor Cycle Sur Neuf Gouaches D'Alexandre Calder, 1962 (Box 10)
    - Catalogs for Salvatore Scarpitta's exhibition "Oeuvres de 1958 a 1964", 1973 (Box 10)
    - Invitation to Sadruddin Aga Khan's wedding, 1972 (Box 10)
    - RSVP card for Tal-Coat exhibition, 1970 (Box 10)
  - File VIII
    - Un Divertissement--Franz Kafka, 1938 (Box 10)
    - Robert Motherwell catalog and engraving, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
    - Joan Miro Oeuvre Graphique Original, 1961 (Box 10)
    - Postcard from Antonio Saura, 1952 (Box 10)
    - Calendar/address books, circa 1948, undated (Box 10)
    - "Tel un Jour de Fete" prints by Georg Baselitz and Stephan Brunner, 1993 (Box 10)
    - Portrait of Emmanuel Benador by Hawk Virgona, undated (Box 10)
    - Solange Kowalski print, 2010 (Box 10)
    - Photographs from Alberto Burri exhibition, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Photograph of Stella Benador, 1976 (Box 10)
    - Photograph of Ruth Caflish, undated (Box 10)
    - Erik Desmazieres etching/card, 2012 (Box 10)
    - Genvieve Asse print, undated (Box 10)
    - Pierre Tal-Coat signature and watercolors, undated (Box 10)
    - Pierre Tal-Coat drawings, undated (Box 10)
    - Images of Tal-Coat exhibition installation, 2009 (Box 10)
    - Pietro Sarto print, undated (Box 10)
    - Daniel Cordier exhibition invitation, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Albert Edgar Yersin card, 1976 (Box 10)
    - International Festival of Music Luzern program, 1978 (Box 11)
    - Autoportrait--Hans Hartung, 1976 (Box 11)
    - Couer de la cite par Robert Barradi, 1997 (Box 11)
    - Commune Presence--Rene Char, 1964-1965 (Box 11)
    - Passage de la Visitation--Andre Frenaud, 1956 (Box 11)
    - 100-Mile Race--Salvatore Scarpitta, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Dessins--Lucio Fontana, 1969 (Box 11)
    - Oeuvres Recentes--Tal-Coat, 1970 (Box 11)
    - Opere Scelte di Artisti Americani, 1961 (Box 11)
  - Uncollected notes, 1982-1985
    - Articles and conference notes, circa 1982-1985 (Box 12)
    - Art and music masterclass notes, circa 1983-1984 (Box 12)
      Materials include notes on Sergiu Celibidache masterclasses (lead by Traute Simmonds) and notes on Hans Hotter masterclasses.
    - Edwin Engelberts' notes on George Braque's creative role in cubist collage, 1984 (Box 12)
- Musical recordings, 1980-1993; Series IV; 1.42; (2 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Contains electronic and analog media owned by Jacques Benador with packaging autographed by the artists.
  - 50 ans de Carriere-Vol. 1 (1938-1960)--Magda Olivero, 1990; 1 (Box 13)
  - Franz Schubert Lieder Recital--Hans Hotter, Bass-Bariton/Michael Raucheisen, Piano, 1980; 1 (Box 14)
  - Les Introuvables d'Elisabeth Schwarzkopf, 1983; 2 (Box 14)
- Artwork, 1952-1970, undated; Series V; 2.33; (1 container)
  Contains original artworks given to Jacques Benador, including works by artists affiliated with the Jacques Benador Gallery.
  - Pierre Aleschinsky: lithograph for Affice Galerie, circa 1958 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Avigdor Arikha: portrait of Jacque Benador, circa 1952-1953 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Arman: Sans Titre (Violon) lithograph, circa 1970 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Jacques Benador: Matta sign, undated (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Max Ernst: untitled etching and aquatint, 1964 (Box 15 (Oversize))